<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on B. Ogan Mancarci</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on B. Ogan Mancarci</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Building an Interactive Fiction System for D&amp;D 5e</title>
      <link>/5e-interactive-fiction/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/5e-interactive-fiction/</guid>
      <description>Picking the adventure format (16-02-2020) Parsing the files (27-02-2020) Dealing with maps (14-02-2020) UI design (05-03-2020) Diversion: gameicons package (05-03-2020)   Some time ago I noticed an interesting product on DM’s Guild. Someone has written a series of solo adventures that are played in a similar manner to choose your own adventure games of the good old days. An adventure comes as a pdf file, describing a scene, presenting the player with options and directing the player to another section in the pdf file based on their choices.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using different/modified version of the same package</title>
      <link>/multiple-package-versions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/multiple-package-versions/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes a package on CRAN doesn’t behave quite as you would like. Maybe a change introduced broke your workflow so you want an older version, maybe you want to add additional functionality and the maintainer is uninterested in incorporating your changes which may not fit the scope or they are simply inactive and inaccessible. Now you have a version of the package that you need that conflicts with CRAN.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interactive visualisation of MRI images in R</title>
      <link>/mri-viz/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/mri-viz/</guid>
      <description>About a year and a half ago, my doctor in Canada requested me to get an MRI while trying to understand why am I having chronic headaches. I requested a copy of those files before going back to Turkey for a holiday to show them to another doctor so I ended up with a CD containing the raw data. I don’t normally work with MRI data but I did port a javascript library for MRI visualisation to R in a hackaton so I figured it shouldn’t be too hard to get a simple interactive visualisation of my own brain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updating the good old Homologene database</title>
      <link>/homologene-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/homologene-update/</guid>
      <description>Homologene What is wrong with homologene? Updating homologene gene IDs Updating homologene gene symbols Update:  Bibliography   Homologene I am the author of a small package called homologene. The package wraps the identically named homologene database released by NCBI. This database includes information about genes that are homologues/orthologues of each other. It is structured as a simple table. One can simply access it by doing
library(readr) library(magrittr) library(dplyr) dir.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Note to self: Fine tuning the site</title>
      <link>/note-to-self-fine-tuning-the-site/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/note-to-self-fine-tuning-the-site/</guid>
      <description>Static resource organization Code cleanup A wild issue appeared Homepage   This is still me rambling about the building process of this site but I have a better idea how things work. It seems like for now this blog is mostly about itself. I am generally happy with how things look but there are still a few visible and invisible changes I want to make to the site.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Note to self: How did I set up this site</title>
      <link>/note-to-self-how-did-i-set-up-this-site/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/note-to-self-how-did-i-set-up-this-site/</guid>
      <description>Baseline Basic set-up Font-awesome (and emojis) [[menu.main]] Children A favicon Category links Google analytics and disqus Homepage   This is mostly personal ramblings about how exactly this site is born. Kept for later reference. It’s not a tutorial. Just a description of every single step I followed to build this. It will include dead ends and obvious mistakes. It might be somewhat educational but I know nothing about Hugo and very little about web design so it might also include misguided attempts at pretty much everything.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is your D&amp;D character rare? II: Off-brand edition</title>
      <link>/dndstats/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/dndstats/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Is Your D&amp;amp;D Character Rare? II Is your character archetype rare? Is your alignment rare? Are your feat choices rare? Is your multiclass combination rare? Is power gaming rare? Are your spells rare? Is your game day rare? About the data Data access About this document Changelog   Edited: 9 September 2018 (see changlelog)
Introduction About a year ago FiveThirtyEight published a short article called “Is Your D&amp;amp;D Character Rare?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>